Stuti Verma

+91-7073119334

stutiverma.developer@gmail.com

Banasthali University

I have 6.5 years of experience as a software developer. Throughout my career, I have worked across organizations of different sizes and contributed to building products from scratch to scale and also to existing products which includes end-to-end features. For the past 5 years, I'm building a community called Women Who Code Delhi, which has helped me strengthen my network and given a place to share my knowledge with people from diverse backgrounds.

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead - Engineering / SDE - II

Shiprocket/Pickrr (Product: Rocketbox)

Jun 2022 — Dec 2022

Remote

- Worked with Rocketbox, a part of Shiprocket group of companies and a B2B logistics aggregator platform with multi-carrier cargo shipping support and 28,000 serviceable pincodes
- Led the product integration of Rocketbox after Pickrr acquired it to 15K sellers and 1M shipments per month
- Boosted API performance by lowering average api latency by 98%
- Built notification engine from scratch to provide real-time shipment tracking updates and increase user-engagement by 12%
- Optimized database indexes to release 500 MB of unused storage
- Implemented logging mechanism, improved existing Sentry error tracking and Elasticsearch-Kibana logging search to enable 90% faster error detection and issue analysis
- · Monitored application performance, debugged and solved performance problems with data
- Mentored team members, established development guidelines, authored code reviews, refactored codebase, managed a team
 Tools: Python, Django, DRF, Docker, AWS, Celery, CI/CD, NewRelic, Sentry, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Filebeat, Jira, Git

Senior Software Engineer

Digital Green (Microsoft Research project)

Jan 2020 — Jun 2022

Remote

- Managed a team of 3 developers to build end-to-end solutions for farmers
- Developed minimal-click user-friendly platform from scratch to deliver soil and weather-based agricultural advisories to **75K farmers** (**30**% women farmers). The adoption rate was **60**%.
- Designed and developed IVR system single-handedly to reach across 100,000 farmers to provide agricultural advisories in 4
 different languages and increase Farmer Producer Organizations' revenue by 20%
- Researched, designed system architecture and developed WhatsApp chatbots for 3 Indian states in 3 languages for 4 crops to
 reach 50,000 farmers with timeline-based advisories throughout the cropping season to help them attain defined quality
 parameters and meet market requirements
- Architectured TARA project aided by Walmart Foundation and worked on MIT Solve 2020 Finalist Loop by Digital Green Tools: Python, Django, Docker, RabbitMQ, EC2, S3, AWS, SQL, Node, Javascript, Redis, Jira, Git, Confluence, Github Actions

Software Engineer

Incedo Inc. (previously Indiabulls Technology Solutions)

Aug 2016 — Jan 2020

Gurgaon

- Developed 15 android application features (courses page with Horizontal and Vertical Recycler View, navigation drawer, custom toolbar, code features using volley and gson libraries, developed screens like welcome, login, payment options and signup pages using XML in Android Studio for different screen sizes like mobile, web and tablet view) for a US-based educational online streaming platform with 840K+ monthly viewers and 500K+ app downloads on Playstore
- Pitched 9 client-POCs to senior management to increase business for 5 US-based telecom, fintech & healthcare major firms Tools: Java, Android, Web-Services, Spring, Maven, Angular, Python, R, pandas, matplotlib, RPA, UiPath, Blockchain

EDUCATION

Banasthali University, B.Tech. in Electronics and Communication Engineering

2012 - 2016

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE & EXTRACURRICULARS

Director, Women Who Code - Delhi

2017 — Present

- I engaged with women-in-tech through various webinars. I was exposed to partnerships and sponsorships with enterprises, startups, communities and Google Developer Groups for conferences & in-person events
- I have developed a strong network with DevRel in Delhi-NCR. I have got first-hand exposure of managing partnerships, sponsorships and collaborations with communities, enterprises and startups.
- Initiated mentorship program for females which had more than 4500 registrations over a span of 4 years
- Community's Growth: Reached audience of 10K women-in-tech through 15+ online & offline events in 5 yrs

College Activities, 2012 - 2016: Founder of College Electronics Club, Events Head at College Annual Technical Festival Organizing Committee Member, Graduate Student Placement Cell Coordinator